Partial Guide to the I. Edward Kiev Papers, circa 1860 - circa 1980 K0001
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Artifacts, circa 1800-circa 1970; K0001 Series 6; 5 linear feet (Box 43, Box 34, Box 55, Box 28, Box 21, Box 20, Box 23, Box 22, Box 25, Box 24, Box 27, Box 26, Box 31, Box 33, Box 29, Box 30, Box 36, Box 17, Box 19, Box 48)
  - Hammond folding typewriter, undated (Box 43, Folder 975)
    In a letter from Phyllis Kiev (Rabbi Kiev's daughter-in-law) to the Gelman Library dated 04/15/98, she states, "We recently had the machine cleaned and reconditioned by the Tytell Typewriter Company of New York City at a cost of over $1000, which cost Mr. Tytell at least $2000 in acquiring parts for it. Though the "K" key does not quite match the others in terms of color, this was the best that he could do under the circumstances. Tytell claims that this machine is similar to one that is currently on display in the British Museum.
    Following the tendency of the times for lightness and complactness in typewriting machines, the Hammond Company has condensed the features of its standard machine into a folding typewriter which has the full capacity of the large machine, taking any width of paper and carrying two sets of type, with variable spacing between the characters (Information from "Condensed History of the Writing Machine").
    Included are two spool covers and two articles which address the subject of Hammond typewriters. Also included is one ribbon and one semi-circular shuttle in plastic wrap (both contained in a small box).
  - Artifact, undated (Box 55, Folder 1889)
    Text in English and Hebrew. Album of postcards from Bezalel with painted wooden covers.
  - Artifact, 1973 (Box 55, Folder 1890)
    Coin encased in blue velvet lined wooden box. Text on coin: "Israel's 25th Anniversary." Text on plaque inside of box: "Presented to Rabbi I. Edward Kiev, Hebrew Union College - Jewish Institute of Religion, Board of Governors Meeting, Jerusalem 1973."
  - Artifact, undated (Box 55, Folder 1891)
    Hebrew and English text. Adjustable and collapsable wood book shelf with stained pictures.